Guide to the Simmons Lumber Company (Williamston, NC) Records, 1878-1936 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Simmons Lumber Company (Williamston, NC) records 1878-1936 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Simmons Lumber Company (Williamston, NC)
37 Linear Feet 27,738 Items
Lumber company in Williamston, NC, founded by Dennis Simmons.
Correspondence, accounts, account books, ledgers, deeds, pay lists, bills, receipts, and other records of the Simmons Lumber Company of Williamston, NC. The papers date from 1878-1936 and relate to all aspects of the lumbering business in North Carolina, from the purchase of timber lands to the shipment of finished board.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Simmons Lumber Company (Williamston, NC) Records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library in 1957.
Collection Overview
Correspondence, accounts, account books, ledgers, deeds, pay lists, bills, receipts, and other records of the Simmons Lumber Company of Williamston, NC. The papers date from 1878-1936 and relate to all aspects of the lumbering business in North Carolina, from the purchase of timber lands to the shipment of finished board.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Simmons, Dennis
Simmons Lumber Company (Williamston, NC)
Lumber trade -- North Carolina
Lumber trade -- Records
Lumbering -- North Carolina
Timber -- North Carolina
Industries -- North Carolina
Contents of Collection
- Correspondence Series, 1879-1930 and undated, (26 boxes)
  - 1879-1905 Jan. (Box 1)
  - 1905 Jan.-Apr. (Box 2)
  - 1905 Apr.-July (Box 3)
  - 1905 July-Sept. (Box 4)
  - 1905 Oct.-Dec. (Box 5)
  - 1906 Jan.-Mar. (Box 6)
  - 1906 Apr.-June (Box 7)
  - 1906 July-Sept. (Box 8)
  - 1906 Sept.-Nov. (Box 9)
  - 1906 Nov.-1907 Jan. (Box 10)
  - 1907 Jan.-Apr. (Box 11)
  - 1907 Apr.-May (Box 12)
  - 1907 June-July (Box 13)
  - 1907 Aug.-Oct. (Box 14)
  - 1907 Nov.-Dec. (Box 15)
  - 1908 Jan.-May (Box 16)
  - 1908 May-Aug. (Box 17)
  - 1908 Aug.-1909 Jan. (Box 18)
  - 1909 Feb.-Mar. (Box 19)
  - 1909 Apr.-May (Box 20)
  - 1909 June-July (Box 21)
  - 1909 July-Sept. (Box 22)
  - 1909 Sept.-Oct. (Box 23)
  - 1909 Oct.-Nov. (Box 24)
  - 1909 Dec.-1922 (Box 25)
  - 1930 and undated (Box 26)
  - Letters, 1901-1902 (Volume 1-2)
  - Letters, 1903 (Volume 3-4)
  - Letters, 1903-1904 (Volume 5)
  - Letters, 1904 (Volume 6-7)
  - Letters, 1904-1905 (Volume 8)
  - Letters, 1905 (Volume 9-10)
  - Letters, 1905-1906 (Volume 11)
  - Letters, 1906 (Volume 12-14)
  - Letters, 1907 (Volume 15-18)
  - Letters, 1907-1908 (Volume 19)
  - Letters, 1908 (Volume 20-24)
- Legal Papers Series, 1853-1936, (3 boxes)
  - 1853-1897 (Box 26)
  - 1898-1906 (Box 27)
  - 1907-1936 (Box 28)
- Miscellany Series, (1 box)
  - Misc. materials (Box 29)
- Financial Papers Series, 1890-1919, (12 boxes)
  - Bills and Receipts
    - 1890-1909 (Box 29-39)
    - 1910-1919 (Box 40)
- Volumes Series, (1 box)
  - Volumes (Box 40)